indear.in 2017-05-25

# Indian Wedding Planning Ideas | Indear.in

### Privacy Policy

  * Your privacy is important to Indear. This privacy policy ("Policy") provides information about the personal information that Indear collects, and the ways in which Indear uses that personal information. Please read the Policy in totality to learn about our information gathering and dissemination practices.
  * The Policy is subject to change at any time and Indear is not obliged in any manner to give prior notice for the same. To be aware of any changes to our Privacy Policy, please review this Policy periodically.
  * By visiting this Website you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Policy and Terms of Use. If you do not agree with the aforesaid, please do not use or access our Website.
  * By mere access or use of the Website, you expressly consent to our use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with this Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the Terms of Use. 

### Collection of Personally Identifiable Information and other Information

  * When you access or use Website, we collect and store your Personal Information which is provided by you from time to time during the course of your use or  access of Website in any manner across all platforms of use. The purpose of doing so is to improve the Website experience and services offered and to provide you with a safe, efficient, smooth and customized experience. We may also collect Personal Information from you that we consider necessary for achieving this  purpose. "Personal Information" shall mean information disclosed by or obtained from any user of the Website and includes name, age, payment processing details, any other personal details capable of identifying a person and any other information about the user (including any literary or artistic works) that the user willingly submits to the Website.
  * In general, you can browse the Website without telling us who you are or revealing any Personal Information about yourself. Once you give us your Personal Information, you are not anonymous to us. Where possible, we indicate which fields are required and which fields are optional. You always have the option to not provide information by choosing not to use a particular service or feature on the  Website.
  * We may automatically track certain information about you based upon your behavior, acts and omissions on our Website. We use this information for the purposes of internal research on our users' demographics, interests, and behaviour to better understand, protect and serve our users a better experience on our Website. This information is compiled and analysed on an aggregated basis. This information may include the date and time of visiting the Website, your IP address, the type of browser being used etc.
  * We use data collection devices such as "cookies" (“Cookies”) on certain pages of the Website to help analyse our web page flow, measure promotional effectiveness, and promote trust and safety. Cookies are small files placed on your hard drive that assist us in providing our services. We offer certain features that are only available through the use of Cookies. We place both permanent and temporary Cookies in your computer's hard drive. The Cookies do not contain any of your personally identifiable information.
  * We also use Cookies to allow you to enter your password less frequently during a session where a ‘session’ is defined as one individual visit to the Website. and for information that helps us improve the services offered to you by the Website. Most Cookies are "session cookies," implying that they are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end of a session. You are always free to decline our Cookies if your browser permits, although in that case you may not be able to use certain features on the Website and you may be required to re-enter your password more frequently during a session.
  * Additionally, you may encounter "Cookies" or other similar devices on certain pages of the Website that are placed by third parties. We do not control the use of Cookies by third parties nor are we in any way responsible for the same.
  * If you send us personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the Website, we may collect such information into a file specific to you and we will not be obliged to notify you in any manner with respect to such information being collected.
  * We collect Personal Information from you when you set up a free account on the Website and become a registered member. While you can browse some sections of  our Website without being a registered member, certain activities (including saving of Content and placing an order) do require registration. We do use your Personal Information to send you correspondences based on your activities and behavior on the Website.

### Use of Demographic / Profile Data / Your Information 

  * We use Personal Information to provide the services you request and those otherwise offered by the Website. To the extent we use your Personal Information to market to you, we will provide you the ability to opt-out of such uses. We use your Personal Information for a number of purposes including but not limited to resolve disputes; troubleshoot problems; help promote a safe service; measure consumer interest in our products and services, inform you about online and offline offers, products, services, and updates; customize your experience; detect and protect us against error, fraud and other criminal activity; enforce our terms and conditions; and as otherwise described to you at the time of collection.
  * In our efforts to continually improve our product and service offerings, we collect and analyse demographic and profile data about our users' activity on our Website.
  * We identify and use your IP address in particular to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our Website and for other purposes that would help improve the services offered to you on the Website and provide more services in the future.

### Sharing of Personal Information

  * We may share any Personal Information with our other affiliates to help detect and prevent identity theft, fraud and other potentially illegal acts; correlate related or multiple accounts to prevent abuse of our services; and to facilitate joint or co-branded services that you request where such services are provided by more than one corporate entity. Those entities and affiliates may not market to you as a result of such sharing unless you explicitly opt-in.
  * We may disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or other legal process. We may disclose Personal Information to law enforcement offices, third party rights owners, or others in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to: enforce our Terms and Conditions or the Policy; respond to claims that an advertisement, posting or other content violates the rights of a third party; or protect the rights, property or personal safety of our users or the general public.
  * We will share / sell some or all of your Personal Information with another business entity should we (or our assets) plan to merge with, or be acquired by that business entity, or re-organization, amalgamation, restructuring of business. Should such a transaction occur, that other business entity (or the new combined entity) will be required to follow this privacy policy with respect to your Personal Information.

### Links to Other Sites

Our Website links to other websites that may collect personally identifiable information about you. Indear is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those linked websites or their use of any information provided by you. Indear cannot guarantee or verify the contents of any externally linked website despite our best efforts. Users should therefore note they click on external links at their own risk and Indear cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any external links mentioned. 

### Security Precautions

Our Website has stringent security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control. Whenever you change or access your account information, we offer the use of a secure server. Once your information is in our possession we adhere to strict security guidelines, protecting it against unauthorized access. 

### Choice/Opt-Out

  * We provide all users with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving non-essential (promotional, marketing-related) communications from us on behalf of our partners, and from us in general, after becoming a registered member/ setting up a free account.
  * If you do not want to receive Indear newsletters or any other communication from Indear, please visit unsubscribe.

### Advertisements on Indear

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. Please be aware that you may click on a sponsored external link at your own risk and Indear cannot be held liable for any damages or implications caused by visiting any external links mentioned. 

### Your Consent 

By using the Website and/ or by providing your information, you consent to the collection and use of the information you disclose on the Website in accordance with this Policy, including but not limited to your consent for sharing your information as per this Policy. 

### Governing Law and Jurisdiction

This Policy shall be governed by the laws of India.
